# Liam Keane

#### SUMMARY

I've had a very broad range of self-taught, technical interests from an early age including Coding, Computer Vision, Gaming, VR, Artificial Intelligence, Electronics and Robotics.

Importantly, IT was a career in our house, so I also learned these topics in the context of real customer/user experience, being self-driven vs teamwork, delivery vs perfection, industry vs academia and amateur vs professional.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Internship: Amazon Web Services, Aurora (AWS) - 19/7/2021 to 11/6/2022

- Usage of Python, JavaScript & PostgreSQL.
- Implemented RDS IAM Authentication for DB connections in a scalable system.
- Designed, planned, and developed User Interaction tracking and analysis for internal websites.
- Amazon style of writing and communication.

## Commercial Product: Peek <a href="http://get-peek.com">http://get-peek.com</a> - 1/2020 to present

- Uses a webcam and head-tracking to turn one physical screen into three virtual screens (think "Lenticular Image").
- Designed, prototyped (Python), wrote (C#) and marketed the entire project & website (enhanced with PHP & JavaScript in WordPress).
- CryptoLens licensing integration & WooCommerce order tracking.

## Commercial Product: Draoi http://draoi.ie - 9/2015 to 1/2019

- A virtual reality game I co-wrote for SteamVR & Oculus Rift, using the Unity engine.
- · Covered every part of game development, from conception to publishing on Steam.
  - o Created a "point cloud", gesture-based spell-casting system for the base game mechanic.
  - o Introduction of multiplayer and other features throughout the course of development.
  - o Creation and adaptation of art assets; 3D Modelling, Texturing.

#### Work Experience: Troll Inc. - 9/2016 to 12/2016

- Gained valuable experience in the flow of game development.
- Tested games that were in development.
- Created an art asset for a game and had the opportunity to learn from the source code.
- Great relationship with everyone on the team.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Ulster University Magee - 9/2019 to 5/2023

Derry, N. Ireland

BSc Hons in Computer Science

# St. Eunan's College - 8/2013 to 6/2019

Letterkenny, Ireland

Leaving Certificate.

#### **SKILLS**

- Proficient in C#, Python and Java. I've released two commercial products.
- Familiar with C/C++, Microsoft UWP (C#), PHP, JavaScript.
- Familiar with IDEs like Visual Studio, VS Code, Android Studio, IntelliJ and more.
- Operating Systems/Platforms: Windows, Android, Various Linux installations.
- Experienced Tools: Unity, Blender, Solidworks, Adobe Suite, Git (Github Desktop & SourceTree), Audio and Video editing (Premiere Pro, Audacity, Cubase), 3D Printing Slicers (Simplify3D & Cura), VirtualBox, Trello.
- Hardware (PC config/assembly, design/solder devices from scratch, etc).
- Helped maintain laptops, projectors, printers etc. at school I was the "go to" at a very young age.
- Arduino and Raspberry Pi experience, basic electronics/robotics, voice and facial recognition.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Received the SSE Airtricity Scholarship.
- Won the Irish Science Teachers Association (ISTA) Senior Science Quiz 2018, in a team of three, from 1100 competitors nationwide.
- Won UK Sportshall Championship 2015, representing Co. Donegal in a team of 7.
- Competition in: 100m, Shot Put, Standing Triple Jump and 400m Relay.
- Placed Top 6 in the A.I. N.I. Hackathon, having never competed before.
- Team Captain for Formula One in Schools 2017. Placed 4th with an award for Fastest Car.
  - Great experience in coordination and motivation.
  - Contact and communication to multiple businesses through email, phone, and visits.
  - o Collection and arrangement of information from team members for submission.
  - A general knowledge of every member's job, such as CAD, Marketing, Manufacturing and more.
  - Wrote a VR application to view our car model, for the exhibition.
- Deputy Head Boy in St. Eunan's College for 6th year. Responsibilities involved:
  - o Organising all the Prefects on a rota for after-school events.
  - Organisation of the rota for lunchtime canteen work.
  - o Representing the school at external events.
- Grade 4 Piano.
- Held 1st place in Beat Saber VR in Ireland, recorded on scoresaber.com.
- Ran training sessions at school on Blender and Unity.

#### LINKS

# http://linkedin.com/in/liam-keane

http://get-peek.com Commercial desktop C# system that uses a webcam to track head movement and simulate 3 displays (like a "lenticular" image).

http://draoi.ie Multiplayer VR game I co-developed using a custom "gesture recognition" system to cast spells.